<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental Health on Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental Health on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:37:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unemployment - Phase I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unemployment-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:37:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unemployment-i/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;iframe data-testid=&#34;embed-iframe&#34; style=&#34;border-radius:12px&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/5vGzsfpKWggKf7xh1xj1iC?utm_source=generator&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last four months have been as precious as gems because I spent them in my home, in my bed, doing absolutely nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phase literally feels like a scene from the movie VIP (Velaiyilla Pattathari)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad wakes me up with a scolding, but I stay in bed. He then goes to the extreme and turning off the fan to make sure I wake up! Finally, I rise around 9 AM. After some personal tasks, I have breakfast and catch up on TV. Then, I open my laptop to check my emails&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Decides for You?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/who-decides-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 21:37:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/who-decides-for-you/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been thinking about how often people try to interfere with decisions that are really no one’s business but your own. Not just close family, but people outside that circle. Distant relatives, neighbors, family friends, and sometimes even people who barely know you. They ask questions like, “Why didn’t you tell me first?” or “You should’ve asked me,” as if your personal choices need to go through some kind of approval system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Night You Decide to Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-night-you-decide-to-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 21:22:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-night-you-decide-to-change/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There comes a night was very quiet, a little heavier than usual and you realized that you’ve messed up your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in a dramatic or world-ending way, but in a way that makes you feel uncomfortable in your own skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/v9v4h2rb3y4b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t hit all at once. It arrives in waves,
A little shame.&lt;br&gt;
A little fear.&lt;br&gt;
A little “Who have I become?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, something surprising shows up,
&lt;strong&gt;Guilt.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Grateful and Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-grateful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 21:06:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-grateful/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to share a childhood incident that made me grateful for everything and taught me to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the ages of 12 and 16, all my friends had bicycles. I also asked my parents to buy me one, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, I finally got my first bicycle. By then, my friends had moved on to motorbikes, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to ride them. All I ever wanted was a bicycle because childhood dreams never fade not just about a cycle, but about everything in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depressed.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 09:26:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://preview.redd.it/lee-chandler-doesnt-leave-you-alone-after-watching-v0-1sodg8fecrge1.png?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=17eac35541dd8ccfca7de73697073fe0478a6449&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I feel depressed these days. Every morning, I wake up to my parents scolding me, and my days go by with very low energy and negative thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any problem occurs at home because of me, they bring up my unemployment. I&amp;rsquo;m just about to finish college in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day by day, my mental health is declining&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why parents scold their children about getting a job after college. There are no students who haven&amp;rsquo;t tried to get a job, everyone tries their best. What can they do if they don&amp;rsquo;t get one?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
