<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techlogs on Mohamed Abdullah</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/</link><description>Recent content in Techlogs on Mohamed Abdullah</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:02:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When AI Crosses the Line</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/when-ai-crosses-the-line/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:02:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/when-ai-crosses-the-line/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;These days, the rapid growth of artificial intelligence feels less exciting and more frightening for many people. What once seemed like a helpful and creative technology is now raising serious concerns about safety, responsibility, and long-term impact. AI systems are becoming more powerful and more accessible, and when that power is placed into open social platforms without strong safeguards, the results can be dangerous. Instead of supporting healthy conversation and creativity, some tools are being misused in ways that harm individuals and society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Open Source Journey in 2025</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 20:56:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year was actually really good, like surprisingly good. I learned a lot of things in tech, broke a lot of things in tech, fixed some of them, and confidently called the rest “features.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between endless Stack Overflow tabs, coffee refills, and “why is this not working??” moments, I grew a lot as a developer and as a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="tech-stuff-happened-a-lot"&gt;Tech Stuff Happened. A Lot.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I learned so many things in tech that my brain occasionally felt like it needed a full reset. New tools, new concepts, and bugs that appeared out of nowhere just to keep me humble.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Signs: How to Spot AI-Written Code in the Wild</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/ai-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:09:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/ai-patterns/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-the-rise-of-the-ai-code-contributor"&gt;Introduction: The Rise of the AI Code Contributor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re living in an interesting time. AI coding assistants have become ubiquitous in modern software development. GitHub Copilot, ChatGPT, Claude, and countless other tools are writing millions of lines of code every day. And while there&amp;rsquo;s nothing inherently wrong with using AI to boost productivity, there&amp;rsquo;s a growing phenomenon that&amp;rsquo;s becoming impossible to ignore: &lt;strong&gt;AI-generated code has a fingerprint&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who reviews code regularly, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed patterns that scream &amp;ldquo;AI wrote this!&amp;rdquo; louder than a syntax error in production. The most glaring? &lt;strong&gt;Emojis in documentation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;obsessively structured comments&lt;/strong&gt;. Let me explain why these patterns are dead giveaways and what they reveal about the current state of AI-assisted development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Open Source Software that I Used in 2025</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/2025-oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:45:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/2025-oss/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="zed"&gt;Zed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/1*CGXsIg5wiNKwvdgQZ3boZg.png" alt="" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Zed as my primary code editor! Zed is an open-source code editor for Linux, macOS, and Windows written using the Rust programming language. It was started by Nathan Sobo, one of the creators of Atom, and is developed by Zed Industries. The editor itself is free to use, but users must pay to use some of the AI features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code editor is sleek and distraction-free! Unlike my brain, which is neither of those things.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zed: A Minimalist Editor for Focused Coding</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/zed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:54:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/zed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://minimo.io/assets/images/blog/zed-editor-2.png" alt="" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been getting tired of VS Code because it’s packed with so many features, menus, and options, all of which can be distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I tried Zed Editor, and my first impression was its minimal UI and distraction-free interface. It&amp;rsquo;s perfect for anyone who wants a simple, focused text-editing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Java development, I&amp;rsquo;m sticking with IntelliJ because JetBrains is still the GOAT when it comes to Java!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for everything else, I’m using Zed for Golang, Python, and pretty much everything else I work on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>So You Want to Get Into Google Summer of Code?</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/gsoc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:11:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/gsoc/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="let-me-be-honest-for-a-minute"&gt;Let Me Be Honest For A Minute&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year a wave of students suddenly becomes deeply passionate about open source the moment they hear something about stipends, selections and resume glory. It is almost poetic. What is less poetic is the fact that most people treat open source like a limited time festival instead of an actual community. If your motivation begins and ends with a program name or a payout, you are already starting on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why SDKMAN?</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/sdkman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:42:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/sdkman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever tried contributing to multiple open-source Java projects, you’ve probably run into this:
Project A needs Java 8, Project B screams for Java 17, and Project C? It says, “Java 21 or I won’t even compile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’ve got two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cry softly into your coffee mug, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use SDKMAN!, the magical version manager for the JVM world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go with option two. It’s less soggy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Maven Tutorial 101</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/mvn101/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:01:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/mvn101/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.programmerhumor.io/2024/07/programmerhumor-io-java-memes-programming-memes-9689c09aebaafe6.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, &lt;strong&gt;Apache Maven&lt;/strong&gt;. The tool that promises to solve your build problems but can occasionally feel like a high school group project where everyone has their own idea of how things should be done. But fear not! Whether you’re new to Maven or just looking to freshen up your knowledge, this guide will help you navigate through the complexities of dependency management and build automation. And yes, we’ve got memes to make it fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is this project important?</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/is-this-project-important/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:33:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/is-this-project-important/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So I had this weird idea: what if I could run Docker containers that only use IPv6, but still let them connect to all the old-school IPv4-only services that most of the internet still runs on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s not something Docker just magically does out of the box, but it turns out&amp;hellip; with a little NAT64 and DNS64 magic, you can actually make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-im-going-to-do-this"&gt;Why I’m going to do This&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? It sounded like a fun project, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t played with NAT64.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deepfake: Ruining Your Life!</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/deepfake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 19:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/deepfake/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="deepfake-technology-a-double-edged-knife"&gt;Deepfake Technology: A Double-Edged Knife&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepfake technology, which involves the manipulation of images, videos, or audio using artificial intelligence, has emerged as one of the most dangerous advancements in recent years. While deepfakes have legitimate uses in entertainment, such as resurrecting deceased celebrities for films or creating AI-generated voices for songs, their negative impact has been growing—particularly in the world of scams and blackmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-deepfake-technology-and-its-uses"&gt;What Is Deepfake Technology and Its Uses?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepfake refers to the use of AI tools or advanced video editing software to create realistic images, videos, or audio that are manipulated to mislead viewers. It has found positive uses in the entertainment industry, with AI-generated voices from late singers and the recreation of deceased actors&amp;rsquo; appearances for films. However, this same technology is being exploited for more malicious purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alaskan Season of Code</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/asoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 11:51:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/asoc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Alaskan Season of Code is a volunteer-based, remote coding program where students collaborate on open-source projects, learning not just technical skills, but also how to work within a diverse, interdisciplinary environment. The program is designed to connect students with faculty mentors from the University of Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can read about the program &lt;a href="https://github.com/uaanchorage/GSoC/blob/main/Alaskan-Season-of-Code.md"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;embed src="https://mdxabu.github.io/assets/asoc.pdf" type="application/pdf" width="100%" height="600px" /&gt;
&lt;h1 id="my-role-in-the-program"&gt;My Role in the Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to participate in this program from May 1st, 2024, to September 15th, 2024, under the mentorship of Dr. Pradeeban Kathiravelu, an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of Alaska Anchorage. During the internship, I worked on the Beehive project, a data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practices with community health metrics in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beware of Fraudulent Loan Apps</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/fraud-loan-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 10:58:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/fraud-loan-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2023/12/fraud-loan-app.jpg" alt="" title="fraud apps" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;fraud apps&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India, there are many fraudulent loan apps out there, like Instant Loan Apps, which offer loans of amounts such as 1000 rupees or some limited amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just think: why would they give you money without any formal process, unlike a bank? A bank is the correct institution for providing loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of apps ask for permission to access your contacts, gallery, and other data on your mobile. Many people click &amp;ldquo;Allow&amp;rdquo; without reading the permissions carefully. As a result, they can view and download your gallery images and contacts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Open Source Journey in 2024</title><link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:00:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/2041638/pexels-photo-2041638.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1" alt="banner" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="my-open-source-journey-in-2024"&gt;My Open Source Journey in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to take my open-source contributions seriously, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible learning experience. I’ve had the opportunity to explore some fantastic open-source projects, tools, and communities, without any bias, and I’ve learned a great deal along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="starting-with-the-docker-maven-plugin"&gt;Starting with the Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="image-figure"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/1250452/pexels-photo-1250452.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1" alt="banner" loading="lazy"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open-source journey began with a contribution to the popular &lt;a href="https://github.com/fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin"&gt;Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. While my contribution was relatively small—updating dependency versions and refactoring a few methods—it taught me a lot about the process of contributing to open-source projects. I was guided through this experience by &lt;a href="https://github.com/rohanKanojia"&gt;Rohan Kanojia&lt;/a&gt;, who showed me the ropes of contributing within an organization and maintaining quality in a collaborative environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>