<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:33:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is this project important?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:33:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I had this weird idea: what if I could run Docker containers that only use IPv6, but still let them connect to all the old-school IPv4-only services that most of the internet still runs on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s not something Docker just magically does out of the box, but it turns out&amp;hellip; with a little NAT64 and DNS64 magic, you can actually make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-im-going-to-do-this&#34;&gt;Why I’m going to do This&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? It sounded like a fun project, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t played with NAT64.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaskan Season of Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 11:51:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alaskan Season of Code is a volunteer-based, remote coding program where students collaborate on open-source projects, learning not just technical skills, but also how to work within a diverse, interdisciplinary environment. The program is designed to connect students with faculty mentors from the University of Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can read about the program &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uaanchorage/GSoC/blob/main/Alaskan-Season-of-Code.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;embed src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/asoc.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role-in-the-program&#34;&gt;My Role in the Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to participate in this program from May 1st, 2024, to September 15th, 2024, under the mentorship of Dr. Pradeeban Kathiravelu, an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of Alaska Anchorage. During the internship, I worked on the Beehive project, a data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practices with community health metrics in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beehive: Leveraging the Expression of Marginalised Peoples.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like this project personally because of the core idea—it was created mainly to help marginalized peoples. Most people do artwork to express their emotions! This kind of project will help researchers understand behavioral and emotional patterns within these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beehive&#34;&gt;Beehive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Data Federation Approach to Analyze Behavioral Health and Complement Healthcare Practice with Community Health Metrics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practice with community health metrics in Alaska using a data federation approach. By leveraging data from various sources, we can gain insights into behavioral health patterns and improve healthcare practices in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey in 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:00:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/2041638/pexels-photo-2041638.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-open-source-journey-in-2024&#34;&gt;My Open Source Journey in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to take my open-source contributions seriously, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible learning experience. I’ve had the opportunity to explore some fantastic open-source projects, tools, and communities, without any bias, and I’ve learned a great deal along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-the-docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Starting with the Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/1250452/pexels-photo-1250452.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open-source journey began with a contribution to the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. While my contribution was relatively small—updating dependency versions and refactoring a few methods—it taught me a lot about the process of contributing to open-source projects. I was guided through this experience by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rohanKanojia&#34;&gt;Rohan Kanojia&lt;/a&gt;, who showed me the ropes of contributing within an organization and maintaining quality in a collaborative environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
