<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:54:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/zed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:54:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/zed/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m tired of VS Code because there are too many features, menus, and options that easily distract me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I tried Zed editor and my first impression was its minimal UI and distraction-free interface. It&amp;rsquo;s a great editor for those who want a simple and focused text editing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using IntelliJ for Java development because JetBrains is the GOAT for Java!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using Zed for Golang, Python, and everything else!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Get Into Google Summer of Code?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:11:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/gsoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-me-be-honest-for-a-minute&#34;&gt;Let Me Be Honest For A Minute&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year a wave of students suddenly becomes deeply passionate about open source the moment they hear something about stipends, selections and resume glory. It is almost poetic. What is less poetic is the fact that most people treat open source like a limited time festival instead of an actual community. If your motivation begins and ends with a program name or a payout, you are already starting on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why SDKMAN?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/sdkman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:42:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/sdkman/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever tried contributing to multiple open-source Java projects, you’ve probably run into this:
Project A needs Java 8, Project B screams for Java 17, and Project C? It says, “Java 21 or I won’t even compile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you’ve got two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cry softly into your coffee mug, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use SDKMAN!, the magical version manager for the JVM world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go with option two. It’s less soggy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven Tutorial 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/mvn101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:01:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/mvn101/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.programmerhumor.io/2024/07/programmerhumor-io-java-memes-programming-memes-9689c09aebaafe6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, &lt;strong&gt;Apache Maven&lt;/strong&gt;. The tool that promises to solve your build problems but can occasionally feel like a high school group project where everyone has their own idea of how things should be done. But fear not! Whether you’re new to Maven or just looking to freshen up your knowledge, this guide will help you navigate through the complexities of dependency management and build automation. And yes, we’ve got memes to make it fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this project important?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:33:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I had this weird idea: what if I could run Docker containers that only use IPv6, but still let them connect to all the old-school IPv4-only services that most of the internet still runs on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s not something Docker just magically does out of the box, but it turns out&amp;hellip; with a little NAT64 and DNS64 magic, you can actually make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-im-going-to-do-this&#34;&gt;Why I’m going to do This&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? It sounded like a fun project, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t played with NAT64.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaskan Season of Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 11:51:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alaskan Season of Code is a volunteer-based, remote coding program where students collaborate on open-source projects, learning not just technical skills, but also how to work within a diverse, interdisciplinary environment. The program is designed to connect students with faculty mentors from the University of Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can read about the program &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uaanchorage/GSoC/blob/main/Alaskan-Season-of-Code.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;embed src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/asoc.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role-in-the-program&#34;&gt;My Role in the Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to participate in this program from May 1st, 2024, to September 15th, 2024, under the mentorship of Dr. Pradeeban Kathiravelu, an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of Alaska Anchorage. During the internship, I worked on the Beehive project, a data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practices with community health metrics in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beehive: Leveraging the Expression of Marginalised Peoples.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is compelling for its core aim of supporting marginalised people. Many individuals use art to express their emotions, and this work helps researchers understand behavioral and emotional patterns within these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beehive&#34;&gt;Beehive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practice with community health metrics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project analyzes behavioral health and complements healthcare practice with community health metrics in Alaska using a data federation approach. By leveraging data from diverse sources, it generates insights into behavioral health patterns and helps improve healthcare practices in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey in 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:00:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/2041638/pexels-photo-2041638.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-open-source-journey-in-2024&#34;&gt;My Open Source Journey in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to take my open-source contributions seriously, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible learning experience. I’ve had the opportunity to explore some fantastic open-source projects, tools, and communities, without any bias, and I’ve learned a great deal along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-the-docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Starting with the Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/1250452/pexels-photo-1250452.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open-source journey began with a contribution to the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. While my contribution was relatively small—updating dependency versions and refactoring a few methods—it taught me a lot about the process of contributing to open-source projects. I was guided through this experience by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rohanKanojia&#34;&gt;Rohan Kanojia&lt;/a&gt;, who showed me the ropes of contributing within an organization and maintaining quality in a collaborative environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
