<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:51:38 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Moment of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/umrah2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:51:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/umrah2025/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This trip was everyone&amp;rsquo;s dream and I got the chance to go!!! It was my first international trip and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even seen many places in Tamil Nadu itself like Ooty and Kodaikanal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Google Summer of Code 2025 first stipend, I planned to perform Umrah in August itself, and I started to enquire about the Umrah packages from different travel agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I booked with one travel agency. After I booked, many people from my neighborhood told me that there were cheaper agencies out there and asked why I chose that one instead of the cheap ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>மௌன பார்வைகள்</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/silent-glances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 22:09:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/silent-glances/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;பார்வை தவறிய புன்னகை,&lt;br&gt;
ஓரமாய் ஒரு நிலா போல.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;சில நேரம் விழி சந்திக்கும்,&lt;br&gt;
அந்த கணம் மட்டும் நீளும்.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;நட்போ? கனவோ? தெரியவில்லை,&lt;br&gt;
நிசப்தம் தான் எல்லாமும் சொல்கிறது.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;நான் பார்த்து நிற்பதை அவள் அறிவாளோ?&lt;br&gt;
அவள் பார்வையில் நான் இருந்தேனா?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ஒரே சந்தேகம் தினமும் மலரும்,&lt;br&gt;
ஆனால் பதில் தராதவள், பூவாகவே உள்ளாள்.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&#34;embed-iframe&#34; style=&#34;border-radius:12px&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/6Xejo9F1hr17aXInilcKZ7?utm_source=generator&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Decides for You?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/who-decides-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 21:37:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/who-decides-for-you/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been thinking about how often people try to interfere with decisions that are really no one’s business but your own. Not just close family, but people outside that circle. Distant relatives, neighbors, family friends, and sometimes even people who barely know you. They ask questions like, “Why didn’t you tell me first?” or “You should’ve asked me,” as if your personal choices need to go through some kind of approval system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, My friend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hbd-my-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 22:10:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hbd-my-friend/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday, My Friend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all Happy Birthday, my friend! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember the very first time I saw you back in college, sitting behind me. Honestly, I was a little scared at first. You looked totally stoned, and I thought, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I better stay away from this guy&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/t751qzpfuvzd1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, surprise! You turned out to be on the same bus route as me. Slowly, we started talking, and I realized you’re actually a really cool guy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this project important?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:33:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/is-this-project-important/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I had this weird idea: what if I could run Docker containers that only use IPv6, but still let them connect to all the old-school IPv4-only services that most of the internet still runs on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s not something Docker just magically does out of the box, but it turns out&amp;hellip; with a little NAT64 and DNS64 magic, you can actually make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-im-going-to-do-this&#34;&gt;Why I’m going to do This&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? It sounded like a fun project, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t played with NAT64.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hearts Rise Unexpectedly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 22:52:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/to-see/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes life can be unpredictable, with sudden downfalls, but some small things can make you feel overwhelmed and great about living!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a moment like this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I feel low sometimes, at that time someone I see coincidentally and my inner self jumps to the sky &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe data-testid=&#34;embed-iframe&#34; style=&#34;border-radius:12px&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/6jyKlPGeDbWWEpvlCq5NnF?utm_source=generator&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;!-- Comment Section Configurations! --&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://giscus.app/client.js&#34;
        data-repo=&#34;mdxabu/mdxabu.github.io&#34;
        data-repo-id=&#34;R_kgDOLs5FtQ&#34;
        data-category=&#34;Blogs&#34;
        data-category-id=&#34;DIC_kwDOLs5Ftc4CrYy-&#34;
        data-mapping=&#34;pathname&#34;
        data-strict=&#34;0&#34;
        data-reactions-enabled=&#34;0&#34;
        data-emit-metadata=&#34;0&#34;
        data-input-position=&#34;top&#34;
        data-theme=&#34;light_protanopia&#34;
        data-lang=&#34;en&#34;
        crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;
        async&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Night You Decide to Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-night-you-decide-to-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 21:22:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-night-you-decide-to-change/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There comes a night was very quiet, a little heavier than usual and you realized that you’ve messed up your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in a dramatic or world-ending way, but in a way that makes you feel uncomfortable in your own skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/v9v4h2rb3y4b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t hit all at once. It arrives in waves,
A little shame.&lt;br&gt;
A little fear.&lt;br&gt;
A little “Who have I become?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, something surprising shows up,
&lt;strong&gt;Guilt.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Grateful and Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-grateful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 21:06:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-grateful/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to share a childhood incident that made me grateful for everything and taught me to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the ages of 12 and 16, all my friends had bicycles. I also asked my parents to buy me one, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, I finally got my first bicycle. By then, my friends had moved on to motorbikes, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to ride them. All I ever wanted was a bicycle because childhood dreams never fade not just about a cycle, but about everything in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depressed.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 09:26:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/depressed/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://preview.redd.it/lee-chandler-doesnt-leave-you-alone-after-watching-v0-1sodg8fecrge1.png?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=17eac35541dd8ccfca7de73697073fe0478a6449&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I feel depressed these days. Every morning, I wake up to my parents scolding me, and my days go by with very low energy and negative thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any problem occurs at home because of me, they bring up my unemployment. I&amp;rsquo;m just about to finish college in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day by day, my mental health is declining&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why parents scold their children about getting a job after college. There are no students who haven&amp;rsquo;t tried to get a job, everyone tries their best. What can they do if they don&amp;rsquo;t get one?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepfake: The AI That’s Too Good at Scamming You and Ruining Your Life!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/deepfake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 19:35:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/deepfake/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deepfake-technology-a-double-edged-knife&#34;&gt;Deepfake Technology: A Double-Edged Knife&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepfake technology, which involves the manipulation of images, videos, or audio using artificial intelligence, has emerged as one of the most dangerous advancements in recent years. While deepfakes have legitimate uses in entertainment, such as resurrecting deceased celebrities for films or creating AI-generated voices for songs, their negative impact has been growing—particularly in the world of scams and blackmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-deepfake-technology-and-its-uses&#34;&gt;What Is Deepfake Technology and Its Uses?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepfake refers to the use of AI tools or advanced video editing software to create realistic images, videos, or audio that are manipulated to mislead viewers. It has found positive uses in the entertainment industry, with AI-generated voices from late singers and the recreation of deceased actors&amp;rsquo; appearances for films. However, this same technology is being exploited for more malicious purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Waste a CS Degree 101: A Masterclass by My College</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/toxic-education-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 11:14:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/toxic-education-system/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-useless-electives&#34;&gt;The Art of Useless Electives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve held onto a lot of vengeance toward my college because of their actions and the useless courses they force on computer science students. Every semester, we have to pick 2-3 open elective subjects. There are so many actually useful electives for computer science like cloud computing or application development, but what do they pick? Social studies and environmental science. Completely unrelated! They choose these subjects because they&amp;rsquo;re easy to teach, not because they&amp;rsquo;re relevant. And even then, they can&amp;rsquo;t teach them properly. Absolutely fucking not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaskan Season of Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 11:51:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/asoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alaskan Season of Code is a volunteer-based, remote coding program where students collaborate on open-source projects, learning not just technical skills, but also how to work within a diverse, interdisciplinary environment. The program is designed to connect students with faculty mentors from the University of Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can read about the program &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uaanchorage/GSoC/blob/main/Alaskan-Season-of-Code.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;embed src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/asoc.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role-in-the-program&#34;&gt;My Role in the Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to participate in this program from May 1st, 2024, to September 15th, 2024, under the mentorship of Dr. Pradeeban Kathiravelu, an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of Alaska Anchorage. During the internship, I worked on the Beehive project, a data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practices with community health metrics in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of Fraudulent Loan Apps: The Hidden Dangers and How to Protect Yourself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/fraud-loan-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 10:58:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/fraud-loan-apps/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.indianexpress.com/2023/12/fraud-loan-app.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;fraud apps&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India, there are many fraudulent loan apps out there, like Instant Loan Apps, which offer loans of amounts such as 1000 rupees or some limited amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just think: why would they give you money without any formal process, unlike a bank? A bank is the correct institution for providing loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of apps ask for permission to access your contacts, gallery, and other data on your mobile. Many people click &amp;ldquo;Allow&amp;rdquo; without reading the permissions carefully. As a result, they can view and download your gallery images and contacts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beehive: Leveraging the Expression of Marginalised Peoples.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/beehive/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is compelling for its core aim of supporting marginalised people. Many individuals use art to express their emotions, and this work helps researchers understand behavioral and emotional patterns within these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beehive&#34;&gt;Beehive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practice with community health metrics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project analyzes behavioral health and complements healthcare practice with community health metrics in Alaska using a data federation approach. By leveraging data from diverse sources, it generates insights into behavioral health patterns and helps improve healthcare practices in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey in 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:00:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techlog/opensource2024/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/2041638/pexels-photo-2041638.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-open-source-journey-in-2024&#34;&gt;My Open Source Journey in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to take my open-source contributions seriously, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible learning experience. I’ve had the opportunity to explore some fantastic open-source projects, tools, and communities, without any bias, and I’ve learned a great deal along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-the-docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Starting with the Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/1250452/pexels-photo-1250452.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open-source journey began with a contribution to the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. While my contribution was relatively small—updating dependency versions and refactoring a few methods—it taught me a lot about the process of contributing to open-source projects. I was guided through this experience by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rohanKanojia&#34;&gt;Rohan Kanojia&lt;/a&gt;, who showed me the ropes of contributing within an organization and maintaining quality in a collaborative environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;08/09/2025 - officially Completed my Google Summer of Code with Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;07/07/2025 - Rejected by &lt;code&gt;Zoho&lt;/code&gt; for the Software Developer role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;08/05/2025 - Got Selected for &lt;code&gt;GSoC 2025&lt;/code&gt; with Organization &lt;code&gt;Alaska&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15/09/2024 - Completed my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/asoc&#34;&gt;Alaskan Season of Code&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;code&gt;Beehive Project&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;01/05/2024 - Rejected for GSoC 2024 with Organization &lt;code&gt;Alaska&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
