<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 20:56:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mdxabu.github.io/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey in 2025</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 20:56:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2025/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year was actually really good, like surprisingly good. I learned a lot of things in tech, broke a lot of things in tech, fixed some of them, and confidently called the rest “features.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between endless Stack Overflow tabs, coffee refills, and “why is this not working??” moments, I grew a lot as a developer and as a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tech-stuff-happened-a-lot&#34;&gt;Tech Stuff Happened. A Lot.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I learned so many things in tech that my brain occasionally felt like it needed a full reset. New tools, new concepts, and bugs that appeared out of nowhere just to keep me humble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Software that I Used in 2025</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/2025-oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:45:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/2025-oss/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;zed&#34;&gt;Zed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/1*CGXsIg5wiNKwvdgQZ3boZg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Zed as my primary code editor! Zed is an open-source code editor for Linux, macOS, and Windows written using the Rust programming language. It was started by Nathan Sobo, one of the creators of Atom, and is developed by Zed Industries. The editor itself is free to use, but users must pay to use some of the AI features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code editor is sleek and distraction-free! Unlike my brain, which is neither of those things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Years for What?</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/uni-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:37:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/uni-scams/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgflip.com/6r90bm.jpg?a490032&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Indian private universities are just scamming students with low-paying jobs with high-paying tuition fees!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was enquiring about colleges before joining! Some so-called top private colleges quoted their fee as 1.5-2 Lakh rupees per year! But I chose a low-fee college, which costs only 50K per year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing my college, those so-called top private college students are also unemployed!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whom to blame? Students skill issue? College exposure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Get Into Google Summer of Code?</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:11:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/gsoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-me-be-honest-for-a-minute&#34;&gt;Let Me Be Honest For A Minute&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year a wave of students suddenly becomes deeply passionate about open source the moment they hear something about stipends, selections and resume glory. It is almost poetic. What is less poetic is the fact that most people treat open source like a limited time festival instead of an actual community. If your motivation begins and ends with a program name or a payout, you are already starting on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Waste a CS Degree 101: A Masterclass by My College</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/toxic-education-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 11:14:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/toxic-education-system/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-useless-electives&#34;&gt;The Art of Useless Electives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve held onto a lot of vengeance toward my college because of their actions and the useless courses they force on computer science students. Every semester, we have to pick 2-3 open elective subjects. There are so many actually useful electives for computer science like cloud computing or application development, but what do they pick? Social studies and environmental science. Completely unrelated! They choose these subjects because they&amp;rsquo;re easy to teach, not because they&amp;rsquo;re relevant. And even then, they can&amp;rsquo;t teach them properly. Absolutely fucking not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaskan Season of Code</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/asoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 11:51:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/asoc/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alaskan Season of Code is a volunteer-based, remote coding program where students collaborate on open-source projects, learning not just technical skills, but also how to work within a diverse, interdisciplinary environment. The program is designed to connect students with faculty mentors from the University of Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can read about the program &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uaanchorage/GSoC/blob/main/Alaskan-Season-of-Code.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;embed src=&#34;https://mdxabu.github.io/assets/asoc.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-role-in-the-program&#34;&gt;My Role in the Program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to participate in this program from May 1st, 2024, to September 15th, 2024, under the mentorship of Dr. Pradeeban Kathiravelu, an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at the University of Alaska Anchorage. During the internship, I worked on the Beehive project, a data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practices with community health metrics in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beehive: Leveraging the Expression of Marginalised Peoples.</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/projects/beehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 16:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/projects/beehive/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is compelling for its core aim of supporting marginalised people. Many individuals use art to express their emotions, and this work helps researchers understand behavioral and emotional patterns within these communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beehive&#34;&gt;Beehive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A data federation approach to analyze behavioral health and complement healthcare practice with community health metrics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project analyzes behavioral health and complements healthcare practice with community health metrics in Alaska using a data federation approach. By leveraging data from diverse sources, it generates insights into behavioral health patterns and helps improve healthcare practices in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey in 2024</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:00:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/techlog/opensource2024/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/2041638/pexels-photo-2041638.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-open-source-journey-in-2024&#34;&gt;My Open Source Journey in 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I decided to take my open-source contributions seriously, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible learning experience. I’ve had the opportunity to explore some fantastic open-source projects, tools, and communities, without any bias, and I’ve learned a great deal along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-the-docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Starting with the Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.pexels.com/photos/1250452/pexels-photo-1250452.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;w=1260&amp;amp;h=750&amp;amp;dpr=1&#34; alt=&#34;banner&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My open-source journey began with a contribution to the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fabric8io/docker-maven-plugin&#34;&gt;Docker Maven Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. While my contribution was relatively small—updating dependency versions and refactoring a few methods—it taught me a lot about the process of contributing to open-source projects. I was guided through this experience by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rohanKanojia&#34;&gt;Rohan Kanojia&lt;/a&gt;, who showed me the ropes of contributing within an organization and maintaining quality in a collaborative environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
