<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Mohamed Abdullah</title>
    <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Mohamed Abdullah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:37:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mdxabu.github.io/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Four Years for What?</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/uni-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:37:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/uni-scams/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;image-figure&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgflip.com/6r90bm.jpg?a490032&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Indian private universities are just scamming students with low-paying jobs with high-paying tuition fees!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was enquiring about colleges before joining! Some so-called top private colleges quoted their fee as 1.5-2 Lakh rupees per year! But I chose a low-fee college, which costs only 50K per year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing my college, those so-called top private college students are also unemployed!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whom to blame? Students skill issue? College exposure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Waste a CS Degree 101: A Masterclass by My College</title>
      <link>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/toxic-education-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 11:14:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdxabu.github.io/posts/toxic-education-system/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-useless-electives&#34;&gt;The Art of Useless Electives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve held onto a lot of vengeance toward my college because of their actions and the useless courses they force on computer science students. Every semester, we have to pick 2-3 open elective subjects. There are so many actually useful electives for computer science like cloud computing or application development, but what do they pick? Social studies and environmental science. Completely unrelated! They choose these subjects because they&amp;rsquo;re easy to teach, not because they&amp;rsquo;re relevant. And even then, they can&amp;rsquo;t teach them properly. Absolutely fucking not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
